Hi guys welcome to my YouTube channel SK
Tech 3.0 so today I will tell you guys
that whatever doubts you have about NPS,
I will clear everything that the
government fund of NPS is like by
default, then if you people want to change the fund in it then
how to do it, that is I will
tell you in every detail what is LC75 LC50
LC25,
I will show you people in two places, which
is the mobile application, how you people can change in that NPS application
and how
you people can change through CRA NSDL by going to Google Chrome.
Let me
show you the mobile display step by step.   The
criteria of the table of 25 is age up
to 35 and if you choose NC 25 then
this asset class is equity, E means equity, C means
corporate, G means government, 25% will
go into corporate equity, 45%
into corporate, 30% into government, as the age keeps
increasing, the equity percentage will keep increasing
and the percentage in the corporate and government
sector will keep increasing.  So now take a
look at the same LC 50, this is LC
50, in this your age criteria is up to 35 and
50% of your total purpose will go in equity,
30 in corporate and 20 in government,
so for whom is this, means those who want to take a little risk and
get a little more return in the long run, only then you
can do it, it is your wish, you
can choose LC 50, LC 25 or LC 75, the
LC of 75 is
not for government employees.  It is only
for those who serve in the private sector.  So let me show you the
official website of NPS,
you can see it by analyzing it.
You can also check from your mobile phone
which
fund has given what percentage return since the implementation of NPS.  So let me go
to Google Chrome.
So you guys have to open Google Chrome here
and you will get this on the NPS website.
So right now here you have to select the category first.
I selected Scheme ER One.
So the tier one account is what
I want to look at.  And in this I
select 1 year.  Within one year,
you can see that four funds are in
negative pay.
AT Bla, Axis, SBI, UTI Look friend, this does
not make any difference in equity in 1 year.
Investment has to be done in the long term.
If seen in 3 years, almost everything
gave good returns.  You can see it in five years, in the
same way, and
you can see it comfortably from your mobile
because you will know everything in it.   It is
written in it that Aditya Birla, HDFC,
ICICI, Kotak, LIC, SBI, UTI,
one thing which was removed from these
in 2025 is Max Live which was a pension fund,
it was removed.  If anyone had funds in it,
it was changed to access.
So now friends, what I will
show you is how you
can easily change the fund manager of NPS
in your mobile and the application which is NPS in your mobile,
probably all the TR One account holders of NPS will
have it, if not then you
can download it from Google Play Store.
So first I will show you how you can make changes in the mobile application which is
NPS application
and I will show you
how you can make changes from Chrome browser.
So guys I have come to my mobile
display.  Let me open the NPS application now.
After opening the NPS application,
click on the three dots here.
After clicking on the three dots, there is
scheme change here.  You have to click on it.
Then here in TR One account,
then here at the bottom, click on Change Scheme Now,
then here in Auto,
click on Moderate Auto Choice.
Then select PFM i.e. Pension
Fund Manager and click on it.
Choose the fund you want here.
Like I chose Axis Bank.
Click on submit here.
Then submit.
Then OTP will come on your mobile.  It will be
submitted after giving OTP.  So guys I just made the
change a few days ago so I am
not submitting.  So this will be
submitted after giving the OTP.  Then within 2 to 3 days it will
show in your NPS account.  The
fund that was changed.  So let me go to Google
Chrome browser now.  I will go there and show you in detail
how to change it from Google Chrome browser.  You have to
open the Chrome browser of your mobile.
Then search CRA NSDL in the search bar and
click on the first website that appears.
I have already set it to desktop mode, that is
why it appeared like this.  I will show you how to get into mobile mode.  It will
appear normal in mobile mode.  So let me do this in desktop mode.
Click on the three dots in the browser.  Click on the desktop side below.
Then it will switch to desktop mode.
Then a new page will open for you.  In this,
after clicking on NPS, you have to enter the user ID
which is your full number and password
capture code and submit it.  Then it will
ask for permission for the location.  You
can say yes or no in this.  There is no problem.
Then a new page will appear to you.  In this,
after clicking on Make Transaction, you have to
click on Change PFM Assist.  Then
this new page will open.  In this your
plan number will be shown and TR type has to be selected.
So in this you have to select TR One NPS.
Then you have to submit it.
This will open a new page for you.
It will show which funds you are currently
investing in.  And it will
also show one more thing that there is a limit of changing the fund
twice a year.  It will also show how many times you
changed it.  Then you have to
submit it.  So guys,
you will have four options in this page.  There are two options in it
which are LC 50 and LC 25, so in LC 50,
50% of your money will be invested in equity.
In LC25, 25% of your money will remain in equity.
So after choosing LC50,
you have to choose the fund manager in it.  [Music]
You can choose whatever you want.
You will get a lot of options in this.
So I chose any one as an example.
Now after that this has to be submitted.
So guys,
OTP will come on your registered mobile number.
After submitting that OTP, the fund you have chosen will start showing in
your NPS account within 2 to 3 days.
So guys, I did not enter the OTP and submit it
because I changed my fund just a few days ago.
So guys, if you liked the video then please
like, comment
and subscribe to the channel.
Share it with your friends.   If you have
any doubt anywhere, please comment.  I
will definitely reply.  See you again
in the next video.